<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Readings on gmnr.github.io</title>
    <link>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Readings on gmnr.github.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 23:17:46 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gmnr.github.io/reading/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tiberio - Grandi Delitti nella Storia</title>
      <link>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/grandi-delitti-tiberio/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 23:17:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/grandi-delitti-tiberio/</guid>
      <description>Yet another book from the series of famous murders.
This time I read about the death of the second Emperor of the Romans: Tiberius Caesar Augustus.
This murder wasn&amp;rsquo;t actually an orchestrated political elimination but rather an unexpected necessity.
The story goes that at a rest in Misenum, from a trip from the island of Capri (where the Emperor had his palace) to Rome, Tiberius fell ill and apparently died.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Giulio Cesare - Grandi Delitti nella Storia</title>
      <link>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/grandi-delitti-giulio-cesare/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 22:21:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/grandi-delitti-giulio-cesare/</guid>
      <description>This one was not a surprise, I am a huge fan of Caesar (although I haven&amp;rsquo;t read any monographs yet) and wanting to know more about the circumstances around the famous dictator&amp;rsquo;s death was only natural to me.
The books provides a detailed account about the events that led up and constituted what is the most famous assassination in History (and there&amp;rsquo;s little doubt about that).
The author, using the outline that has characterized this series about famous murders, first presents the backstory of the murder itself answering questions such as:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Filippo II di Macedonia - Grandi Delitti nella Storia</title>
      <link>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/grandi-delitti-filippo-macedone/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 23:36:37 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/grandi-delitti-filippo-macedone/</guid>
      <description>A bit underwhelming.
The authors try and represent a clear picture of the event surrounding the death of Philip II of Macedon, but the accounts and any historical reconstruction is nearly impossible because of the lack of reliable sources.
Therefore, the narrative delves deeper than I would&amp;rsquo;ve liked into dramatization.
I can recommend it as a very light read before going to bed if you&amp;rsquo;re a novice approaching the subject; but otherwise it lacks substance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Gracchi - Grandi Delitti nella Storia</title>
      <link>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/grandi-delitti-i-gracchi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 20:54:02 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/grandi-delitti-i-gracchi/</guid>
      <description>I quite liked this one;
it is the first book I read in 2021 and the first one I came across from the collection of &amp;ldquo;Grandi Delitti della Storia&amp;rdquo; (that translates into: Great Murders of History), a curated series by Corriere della Sera.
I&amp;rsquo;ve always been fascinated by famous murders as they often are breakpoints in the ebb and flow of History and become catalysts of change.
They are also surprisingly often well documented, either because of the morbidity inherent to human nature or maybe because the are a nice break from the apparent plainness of History.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
