<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Writings on gmnr.github.io</title>
    <link>https://gmnr.github.io/writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Writings on gmnr.github.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 22:34:09 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gmnr.github.io/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Review: Kinesis Advantage 2</title>
      <link>https://gmnr.github.io/writing/kinesis-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 22:34:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gmnr.github.io/writing/kinesis-review/</guid>
      <description>What are ergonomic keyboards anyways? The design, usability and concept of an ergonomic keyboard are enhanced features that provide for a more comfortable (or strictly speaking more anatomically correct) typing experience.
In order to do so an ergonomic keyboard might have one of the following (or all):
 ortolinear keys: the keys are neatly stacked in line, rather than being aligned diagonally key wells: little depressions that account for the different length of your fingers wrist pads: raised palm rests for a more comfortable typing experience  Of course all these &amp;ldquo;improvements&amp;rdquo; come with an hefty premium, that companies charge not only for those upgrades but also for the higher production costs required for an &amp;ldquo;artisanal&amp;rdquo; piece, as these keyboards are hardly mass produced and are almost always mechanic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;More&#34;</title>
      <link>https://gmnr.github.io/writing/more/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 18:15:51 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gmnr.github.io/writing/more/</guid>
      <description>A ship in harbor is safe, but that is not what ships are built for  ## On confrontation I am the kind of person that doesn&amp;rsquo;t like confrontation much (both external and internal). But even so, I recognize the importance of &amp;ldquo;opposition&amp;rdquo;.
I don&amp;rsquo;t mean it literally; I&amp;rsquo;m not suggesting you go challenging everyone and everything in your life but rather that you try and focus inward, always striving to challenge yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My first blog post</title>
      <link>https://gmnr.github.io/writing/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 21:18:45 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gmnr.github.io/writing/first-post/</guid>
      <description>Even a journey of a thousand miles starts with a single step  First steps Here it is&amp;hellip; This is my second blog post, ever.
Why not the first? Because this is the second time that I try blogging.
I&amp;rsquo;m quite excited to start this journey (again), but I&amp;rsquo;m left with some doubts; one above all: will I be able to keep the commitment and write every now and then?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
