<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>gmnr.github.io</title>
    <link>https://gmnr.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on gmnr.github.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 14:34:46 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://gmnr.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Il Lessico dei Greci, Una civiltà in 30 parole</title>
      <link>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/lessico-greco/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 14:34:46 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/lessico-greco/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The idea is interesting, but sometimes I&amp;rsquo;ve felt that the chapter was only going on to fill more space of the book.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve appreciated the little trivia that I didn&amp;rsquo;t know before.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All in all a nice read, but nothing so breathtaking that changed my perspective.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The name-dropping was strong in this one.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;book-details&#34;&gt;Book Details&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;ISBN: 9788832856910&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Published: 2024&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pages: 240&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Harry Potter and the Methods of Rationality</title>
      <link>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/hpmor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 09:27:03 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/hpmor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What a roller coaster!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have never been a big fan of fan-fictions, and it kinda shows&amp;hellip;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;During the read I have changed opinion 4 times about the books, its themes and my general &amp;ldquo;appreciation&amp;rdquo; for it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the end I believe it was a worthy read - I basically devoured the book.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My fears for the ending were unfounded, it ties everything nicely (from a logic&amp;rsquo;s narrative stand point at least).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Grapes of Wrath</title>
      <link>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/grapes-of-wrath/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 10:49:56 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/grapes-of-wrath/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;No wonder this is considered a must read.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It took me a fairly long time to finish, being awfully busy and all, but in the end it&amp;rsquo;s one of the best books I&amp;rsquo;ve&#xA;read in a long time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The character are so very compelling, the story never boring.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The juxtaposition of a narrative chapter with a descriptive one (each winking each other) keeps a rhythm that is inescapable.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From a legibility perspective I especially enjoyed the way the accents of the characters are written.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;From a moral perspective the social criticism is ruthless.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Giulio Cesare: Il Dittatore Democratico</title>
      <link>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/giulio-cesare/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 12:13:32 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/giulio-cesare/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I picked up this book by chance while browsing around in a local library.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The edition I ended up taking had that famous bust of Caesar that now is a popular&#xA;souvenir at the Vatican Museum.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://gmnr.github.io/img/caesar/bust.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Caesar bust, now in the Vatican Museum&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;figcaption&gt;The bust in question&lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I always wanted to read a monograph about the most important (?) man for the Western Civilization.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;(I mean, heck, the various European titles all meant Caesar: Zar, Kaiser, Cesar; and they all emanate from this one Caesar).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Storm Before the Storm: The Beginning of the End of the Roman Republic</title>
      <link>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/the-storm-before-the-storm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 09:50:23 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/the-storm-before-the-storm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mike Duncan is my favorite podcaster.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;He ran &amp;ldquo;The History of Rome&amp;rdquo; podcast from 2007 to 2012 explaining in detail the whole history of&#xA;the Roman Western Empire.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;It ran for 73h total, and I relished every last minute of it! (mostly while commuting by car).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;He then published this book that focuses on a period that is &lt;em&gt;less glamorous&lt;/em&gt;&#xA;than the Fall of the Republic but that is nonetheless fundamental&#xA;in understanding the shift from Republic to Empire.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dizionario Filosofico Napoletano – Detti, motti e proverbi</title>
      <link>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/detti-napoletani/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 09:55:01 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/detti-napoletani/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I procured myself with a dictionary of short laconic Neapolitan sayings,&#xA;in order to pick up some idiomatic expressions and be more colorful when interacting with others.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is a collection of popular proverbs of Neapolitan origin and the for each, the author offers:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The original spelling;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;an italian translation;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;an explanation, that tries to uproot its origin and its application.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nothing really beats a folk saying in efficacy, shortness and effect.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Personal Finance</title>
      <link>https://gmnr.github.io/writing/personal-finance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 12:38:16 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gmnr.github.io/writing/personal-finance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://gmnr.github.io/img/personal-finance/header.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;A cute photo of savings growing out of a pot&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;figcaption&gt;This is how I Imagine my savings growing&lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This was a long time coming post of sorts, as money management in the last 5 years&#xA;has become a relevant &lt;strong&gt;trap&lt;/strong&gt; of my spare time.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;I say trap because I have designed and redesigned the &amp;ldquo;systems&amp;rdquo; with which I manage my money,&#xA;I have watched thousands of pills and tips and tricks on personal finance,&#xA;and have been, all round &lt;strong&gt;absorbed&lt;/strong&gt; by the topic (as I usually get absorbed, which sits one inch short of obsessed).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Soldiers and Silver: Mobilizing Resources in the Age of Roman Conquest</title>
      <link>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/soldiers-and-silver/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 10:16:12 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/soldiers-and-silver/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Finally, after complaining book after book that the authors try to hard to &amp;ldquo;fictionalize&amp;rdquo; history,&#xA;I have found a book rooted in rational analysis on I topic that I really like.&#xA;It does help that the book is none other than the editing and publication of a doctoral dissertation by the author,&#xA;and therefore is steeped in citations and data.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The book compares the &lt;strong&gt;military capabilities&lt;/strong&gt; and related &lt;strong&gt;treasury issues&lt;/strong&gt;&#xA;of five Mediterranean military powers from the year 280 BC to the 168 BC.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Close to the Machine: Technophilia and its discontents</title>
      <link>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/close-to-the-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 08:43:15 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/close-to-the-machine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I devoured this book.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;I was actually surprised that at night, before bed&#xA;I found myself thinking about it and wanting it to read more.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, while it was indeed an enjoyable read, I expected somewhat more.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Approaching the book I expected it to be more of an essay and with a deeper&#xA;technological focus.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Instead it&amp;rsquo;s just a story, which happens to be set in a particularly&#xA;&amp;ldquo;technological period&amp;rdquo; (the late 90s).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The 48 Laws of Power</title>
      <link>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/48-rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2023 20:34:14 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/48-rules/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have seen this book recommended everywhere and so I decided to give it a shot.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Each chapter is a supposed &amp;ldquo;law&amp;rdquo; of power, with a very short summary of the&#xA;dos and dont&amp;rsquo;s and then examples (both in accordance and opposition with the law in&#xA;question) drawn from anecdotes.&#xA;The authenticity of these anecdotes is never in question and yet, I haven&amp;rsquo;t found&#xA;a single source that attests to their legitimacy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting Things Done</title>
      <link>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/gtd/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 10:23:03 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/gtd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I dug in the book with high expectations, confident it would actually&#xA;improve my &amp;ldquo;productivity habits&amp;rdquo; and make me more productive in both&#xA;personal and work life.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The proposition is seducing, who wouldn&amp;rsquo;t want to set aside all the noise and&#xA;the effort required to &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;be organized&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; in favor of just &amp;ldquo;Get Things Done&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Spoiler:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, this method did not help me increase my productivity x10.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-little-bit-of-background&#34;&gt;A little bit of background&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The GTD method is a very famous productivity framework aimed at helping people&#xA;manage their tasks and reach their objectives.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;It conceptualize a way to free your brain of it&amp;rsquo;s resource intensive&#xA;&amp;ldquo;storage capacity&amp;rdquo; allowing for a better allocation of it&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;processing&#xA;capacities&amp;rdquo; (not the author&amp;rsquo;s way of describing things).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Samnes - Amore e Guerra al tempo dei Sanniti</title>
      <link>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/samnes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 08:04:24 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/samnes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I brought this book with me when I moved from Telese to Naples.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;I picked it up because I&amp;rsquo;ve always been interested in history and customs&#xA;of my ancestral people (I come from a small &amp;ldquo;new&amp;rdquo; town, that is located at the&#xA;heart of the historic region that takes its name from the Saminte People), and&#xA;therefore was excited at the idea of learning more about them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#&#34;&gt;Fun Fact:&lt;/a&gt; Telese&amp;rsquo;s name comes from the ancient &lt;em&gt;Telesia&lt;/em&gt; a capital of the&#xA;federation of independent tribes deep in Samnite territory&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Master and Margherita</title>
      <link>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/master-and-margherita/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 19:25:20 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/master-and-margherita/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://gmnr.github.io/img/master-margherita/cat.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;cat&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;figcaption&gt;That&amp;#39;s a very large black cat, or maybe&#xA;it&amp;#39;s an hippo?!&lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My mom first suggested me the book, which she listened to as an audio-book in&#xA;her spare time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;She told me it was a masterpiece, that it was a must read in one&amp;rsquo;s lifetime.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;And indeed it was.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is something deeply poetic in the parallels that the book traces. There&#xA;are a lot of characters in the book (many with complicated Russian names that&#xA;sound all the same), that live seemingly unrelated events, which are all&#xA;triggered by the arrival of the Devil in Moscow and the revelry of his&#xA;companions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breve Storia Della Città di Napoli</title>
      <link>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/storia-napoli/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2022 11:01:47 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/storia-napoli/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I found this book in box that was going to be put away, asked my mom about it&#xA;and she said it was worth a try.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All in all is not a bad read, but my gripe with it is two faced.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First, the style is not appealing to me at all; phrases often digress to offer&#xA;the author a chance to use a certain &amp;ldquo;poetic flair&amp;rdquo; that often clouds the&#xA;understandability of what&amp;rsquo;s being said.&#xA;More often than not, arguments are not presented clearly, or worse grossly&#xA;simplified, to enable the use of effect phrases and poetic licenses that&#xA;accomplish nothing in moving the arguments forward.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Mind for Numbers</title>
      <link>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/a-mind-for-numbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 16:50:14 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/a-mind-for-numbers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The book is a good read; especially if you are a student.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;It can help you adapt and mold your studying strategy in order to maximize your&#xA;retention and recollection.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The book itself is about having &amp;ldquo;a mind for numbers&amp;rdquo; and improve your stats&#xA;while learning STEM topics but I think it truly applies to all fields of&#xA;learning.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What I have not so much liked is that it is heavily oriented towards the&#xA;education system, helping you &amp;ldquo;passing the tests&amp;rdquo; rather than helping you truly&#xA;connect with what you&amp;rsquo;re trying to learn and master it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Never Split the Difference - Negotiating As If Your Life Depended On It</title>
      <link>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/never-split-the-difference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 13:22:39 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/never-split-the-difference/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The book is a condensed vademecum about negotiation, distilled by none other&#xA;than Chris Voss, acclaimed author and top FBI-guy negotiator for more than&#xA;25 years.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before reading it, I didn&amp;rsquo;t know if all the buzz about the book was actually&#xA;due because it is a breathtaking deep dive in the world of negotiations&#xA;or because Chris&amp;rsquo; company, &amp;ldquo;The Black Swan Group&amp;rdquo; has an amazing marketing&#xA;department.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Now, I know it is a little bit of both.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Your Money or Your Life: 9 Steps to Transforming Your Relationship With Money and Achieving Financial Independence</title>
      <link>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/your-money-your-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2021 17:19:37 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/your-money-your-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was really excited for this book; so excited that it actually took me more&#xA;than 4 months to finally finish it (eheh).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I got to this book via a suggestion by &lt;a href=&#34;https://https://retireinprogress.com/&#34;&gt;Mr. Rip&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;that cites it as a very influential read in the journey towards &lt;strong&gt;Financial&#xA;Independence&lt;/strong&gt; (FI from now onward).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-financial-independence&#34;&gt;What is financial Independence?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Technically FI is the status of having enough income to pay one&amp;rsquo;s living&#xA;expenses for the rest of one&amp;rsquo;s life without having to be employed or dependent&#xA;on others. (according to &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Financial_independence&#34;&gt;wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; anyways).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Happiness Advantage</title>
      <link>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/the-happiness-advantage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 14:10:36 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/the-happiness-advantage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The main concept presented in the book is that the &lt;em&gt;very American (and&#xA;puritan)&lt;/em&gt; equation of:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://gmnr.github.io/img/happiness/wrong.png&#34; alt=&#34;the wrong equation&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;is substantially flawed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Instead, corroborated by the recent developments of positive psychology,&#xA;a better recipe to self-actualization might instead be:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://gmnr.github.io/img/happiness/right.png&#34; alt=&#34;the right equation&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Therefore, the author tries to convey a series of guidelines to help the&#xA;readers collect happiness boosts during the day in order to pursue their goals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aldo Moro - Grandi Delitti nella Storia</title>
      <link>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/grandi-delitti-aldo-moro/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 22:27:12 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/grandi-delitti-aldo-moro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I read this book in one night;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As already mentioned in these reviews, I don&amp;rsquo;t particularly like &amp;ldquo;modern&amp;rdquo;&#xA;History (and for me modern is everything that happened less than 1.500 years&#xA;ago); but this beautiful essay by Matteo Albanese showed me that more can be&#xA;told about events whose sources are contemporary to us (as expected) but in&#xA;a way that feels genuine and engaging.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Telling a story that has been written rewritten, conspired about, put on other&#xA;media and much, much discussed is not an easy task, especially from an&#xA;Historical point of view. And yet the way the facts surround the famous&#xA;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;affare Moro&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; are told in this essay specifically outline a new way of&#xA;telling History that I had not imagined.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Facts are not presented in a sensationalized way, but rather by verifying in&#xA;every paragraph the checks and balances, the subtle equilibrium of presenting&#xA;facts in an aseptic way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Giuliano de Medici - Grandi Delitti nella Storia</title>
      <link>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/grandi-delitti-giuliano-medici/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 22:18:28 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/grandi-delitti-giuliano-medici/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am not the biggest fan of the Renaissance;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;I value its importance in the development of the modern world but my&#xA;fascination ends there, I am more of a &amp;ldquo;BC&amp;rdquo; kind of guy (or even &amp;ldquo;early AD&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In any case, the murder of &lt;em&gt;Giuliano&lt;/em&gt; was sure an important step in defining&#xA;the future of Firenze.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;What the book truly offers is an accurate cross section of what life was in the&#xA;late Middle Ages with all its cultural fervor and development.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cicerone - Grandi Delitti nella Storia</title>
      <link>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/grandi-delitti-cicerone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 May 2021 14:59:59 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/grandi-delitti-cicerone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Following the usual format, the book presents the circumstances surrounding the&#xA;fall, the flight and the assassination of Rome&amp;rsquo;s most famous orator: &lt;em&gt;Marcus&#xA;Tullius Cicerone&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In opposition to my likings, it particularly stresses the emotions of&#xA;&lt;em&gt;Cicerone&lt;/em&gt; himself, the indecision, the fear for his family&amp;rsquo;s life, the last&#xA;moments near is villa in Formia.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Such things, as they really went, are forever lost in &lt;em&gt;History&lt;/em&gt;, but in this&#xA;case that awful &lt;strong&gt;dramatization&lt;/strong&gt; that much I dislike, was not out of place.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tiberio - Grandi Delitti nella Storia</title>
      <link>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/grandi-delitti-tiberio/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 23:17:46 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/grandi-delitti-tiberio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yet another book from the series of famous murders.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;This time I read about the death of the second Emperor of the Romans: &lt;em&gt;Tiberius&#xA;Caesar Augustus&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This murder wasn&amp;rsquo;t actually an orchestrated political elimination but rather an&#xA;unexpected necessity.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The story goes that at a rest in Misenum, from a trip from the island of Capri&#xA;(where the Emperor had his palace) to Rome, &lt;em&gt;Tiberius&lt;/em&gt; fell ill and apparently&#xA;died.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;At the time the two candidates for the imperial succession were two teen boys:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Giulio Cesare - Grandi Delitti nella Storia</title>
      <link>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/grandi-delitti-giulio-cesare/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 22:21:41 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/grandi-delitti-giulio-cesare/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This one was not a surprise, I am a huge fan of &lt;em&gt;Caesar&lt;/em&gt; (although I haven&amp;rsquo;t&#xA;read any monographs yet) and wanting to know more about the circumstances&#xA;around the famous dictator&amp;rsquo;s death was only natural to me.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The books provides a detailed account about the events that led up and&#xA;constituted what is the most famous assassination in History (and there&amp;rsquo;s&#xA;little doubt about that).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The author, using the outline that has characterized this series about famous&#xA;murders, first presents the backstory of the murder itself answering questions&#xA;such as:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Filippo II di Macedonia - Grandi Delitti nella Storia</title>
      <link>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/grandi-delitti-filippo-macedone/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 23:36:37 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/grandi-delitti-filippo-macedone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A bit underwhelming.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The authors try and represent a clear picture of the event surrounding the&#xA;death of Philip II of Macedon, but the accounts and any historical&#xA;reconstruction is nearly impossible because of the lack of reliable sources.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Therefore, the narrative delves deeper than I would&amp;rsquo;ve liked into&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;dramatization&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I can recommend it as a very light read before going to bed if you&amp;rsquo;re a novice&#xA;approaching the subject; but otherwise it lacks substance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review: Kinesis Advantage 2</title>
      <link>https://gmnr.github.io/writing/kinesis-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 22:34:09 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gmnr.github.io/writing/kinesis-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-are-ergonomic-keyboards-anyways&#34;&gt;What are ergonomic keyboards anyways?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The design, usability and concept of an ergonomic keyboard are enhanced&#xA;features that provide for a more comfortable (or strictly speaking more&#xA;anatomically correct) typing experience.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In order to do so an ergonomic keyboard might have one of the following (or&#xA;all):&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ortolinear keys&lt;/strong&gt;: the keys are neatly stacked in line, rather than being&#xA;aligned diagonally&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;key wells&lt;/strong&gt;: little depressions that account for the different length of&#xA;your fingers&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;wrist pads&lt;/strong&gt;: raised palm rests for a more comfortable typing experience&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Of course all these &amp;ldquo;improvements&amp;rdquo; come with an hefty premium, that companies&#xA;charge not only for those upgrades but also for the higher production costs&#xA;required for an &amp;ldquo;artisanal&amp;rdquo; piece, as these keyboards are hardly mass produced&#xA;and are almost always mechanic.&#xA;To justify this extra buck, the producers usually add even more extra features&#xA;that make these keyboard more niche. These added functionalities range from&#xA;improved programmability to rear mirrors (I am not even &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=h4-fq8ksZls&amp;amp;ab_channel=LinusTechTips&#34;&gt;kidding&lt;/a&gt; now).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Gracchi - Grandi Delitti nella Storia</title>
      <link>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/grandi-delitti-i-gracchi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 20:54:02 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/grandi-delitti-i-gracchi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I quite liked this one;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;it is the first book I read in 2021 and the first one I came across from the&#xA;collection of &amp;ldquo;Grandi Delitti della Storia&amp;rdquo; (that translates into: &lt;em&gt;Great&#xA;Murders of History&lt;/em&gt;), a curated series by &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Corriere_della_Sera&#34;&gt;Corriere della&#xA;Sera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always been fascinated by famous murders as they often are breakpoints in&#xA;the ebb and flow of History and become catalysts of &lt;em&gt;change&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;They are also surprisingly often well documented, either because of the&#xA;morbidity inherent to human nature or maybe because the are a nice break from&#xA;the &lt;em&gt;apparent plainness&lt;/em&gt; of History.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;One thing is reading about an historical trend, an overarching process that is&#xA;the sum of many little changes accrued during many years, or even decades;&#xA;another matter entirely is the sudden &lt;em&gt;shift&lt;/em&gt; that happens in the polarizing&#xA;moments after a famous murder.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#34;More&#34;</title>
      <link>https://gmnr.github.io/writing/more/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 18:15:51 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gmnr.github.io/writing/more/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://gmnr.github.io/img/more/pier.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;A ship in the harbor&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;figcaption&gt;A ship in harbor is safe, but that&#xA;is not what ships are built for&lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-confrontation&#34;&gt;On confrontation&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am the kind of person that doesn&amp;rsquo;t like confrontation much (both external and&#xA;internal).&lt;br&gt;&#xA;But even so, I recognize the importance of &amp;ldquo;opposition&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t mean it literally; I&amp;rsquo;m not suggesting you go challenging everyone and&#xA;everything in your life but rather that you try and focus inward, always&#xA;striving to challenge yourself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My first blog post</title>
      <link>https://gmnr.github.io/writing/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 21:18:45 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gmnr.github.io/writing/first-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://gmnr.github.io/img/first/start.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;new beginnings&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;figcaption&gt;Even a journey of a thousand miles&#xA;starts with a single step&lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;first-steps&#34;&gt;First steps&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here it is&amp;hellip; This is my second blog post, ever.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Why not the first? Because this is the second time that I try blogging.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m quite excited to start this journey (again), but I&amp;rsquo;m left with some doubts;&#xA;one above all: &lt;em&gt;will I be able to keep the commitment and write every now and&#xA;then?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://gmnr.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gmnr.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://gmnr.github.io/img/about/presentation.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;hello&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Hi, my name is Guido.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;I play music (with varied degrees of success and instruments) and I like&#xA;computers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-computer-conundrum&#34;&gt;The Computer Conundrum&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have no CompSci background, but I am &lt;em&gt;rather enthusiastic&lt;/em&gt; about computers&#xA;(emphasis on both terms).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With no formal education and zero practical knowledge in the field I know&#xA;I won&amp;rsquo;t be working around my passion.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;I actually tried getting hired by a tech-company but I ended up working for&#xA;a big IT name, albeit for a less technical role that I had hoped for.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Maybe one day I will write about that too, maybe not.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What I have read so far</title>
      <link>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
