<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>gmnr.github.io</title>
    <link>https://gmnr.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on gmnr.github.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 23:17:46 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gmnr.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tiberio - Grandi Delitti nella Storia</title>
      <link>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/grandi-delitti-tiberio/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 23:17:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/grandi-delitti-tiberio/</guid>
      <description>begin
Book Details  ISBN: 9771727552415 Published: 2020 Pages: 152  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Giulio Cesare - Grandi Delitti nella Storia</title>
      <link>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/grandi-delitti-giulio-cesare/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 22:21:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/grandi-delitti-giulio-cesare/</guid>
      <description>This one was not a surprise, I am a huge fan of Caesar (although I haven&amp;rsquo;t read any monographs yet) and wanting to know more about the circumstances around the famous dictator&amp;rsquo;s death was only natural to me.
The books provides a detailed account about the events that led up and constituted what is the most famous assassination in History (and there&amp;rsquo;s little doubt about that).
The author, using the outline that has characterized this series about famous murders, first presents the backstory of the murder itself answering questions such as:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Filippo II di Macedonia - Grandi Delitti nella Storia</title>
      <link>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/grandi-delitti-filippo-macedone/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 23:36:37 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/grandi-delitti-filippo-macedone/</guid>
      <description>A bit underwhelming.
The authors try and represent a clear picture of the event surrounding the death of Philip II of Macedon, but the accounts and any historical reconstruction is nearly impossible because of the lack of reliable sources.
Therefore, the narrative delves deeper than I would&amp;rsquo;ve liked into dramatization.
I can recommend it as a very light read before going to bed if you&amp;rsquo;re a novice approaching the subject; but otherwise it lacks substance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Kinesis Advantage 2</title>
      <link>https://gmnr.github.io/writing/kinesis-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 22:34:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gmnr.github.io/writing/kinesis-review/</guid>
      <description>What are ergonomic keyboards anyways? The design, usability and concept of an ergonomic keyboard are enhanced features that provide for a more comfortable (or strictly speaking more anatomically correct) typing experience.
In order to do so an ergonomic keyboard might have one of the following (or all):
 ortolinear keys: the keys are neatly stacked in line, rather than being aligned diagonally key wells: little depressions that account for the different length of your fingers wrist pads: raised palm rests for a more comfortable typing experience  Of course all these &amp;ldquo;improvements&amp;rdquo; come with an hefty premium, that companies charge not only for those upgrades but also for the higher production costs required for an &amp;ldquo;artisanal&amp;rdquo; piece, as these keyboards are hardly mass produced and are almost always mechanic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Gracchi - Grandi Delitti nella Storia</title>
      <link>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/grandi-delitti-i-gracchi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 20:54:02 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/grandi-delitti-i-gracchi/</guid>
      <description>I quite liked this one;
it is the first book I read in 2021 and the first one I came across from the collection of &amp;ldquo;Grandi Delitti della Storia&amp;rdquo; (that translates into: Great Murders of History), a curated series by Corriere della Sera.
I&amp;rsquo;ve always been fascinated by famous murders as they often are breakpoints in the ebb and flow of History and become catalysts of change.
They are also surprisingly often well documented, either because of the morbidity inherent to human nature or maybe because the are a nice break from the apparent plainness of History.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More</title>
      <link>https://gmnr.github.io/writing/more/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 18:15:51 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gmnr.github.io/writing/more/</guid>
      <description>A ship in harbor is safe, but that is not what ships are built for  On confrontation I am the kind of person that doesn&amp;rsquo;t like confrontation much (both external and internal).
But even so, I recognize the importance of &amp;ldquo;opposition&amp;rdquo;.
I don&amp;rsquo;t mean it literally; I&amp;rsquo;m not suggesting you go challenging everyone and everything in your life but rather that you try and focus inward, always striving to challenge yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My first blog post</title>
      <link>https://gmnr.github.io/writing/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 21:18:45 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gmnr.github.io/writing/first-post/</guid>
      <description>Even a journey of a thousand miles starts with a single step  First steps Here it is&amp;hellip; This is my second blog post, ever.
Why not the first? Because this is the second time that I try blogging.
I&amp;rsquo;m quite excited to start this journey (again), but I&amp;rsquo;m left with some doubts; one above all: will I be able to keep the commitment and write every now and then?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://gmnr.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gmnr.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi, my name is Guido.
I play music (with varied degrees of success and instruments) and I like computers.
The Computer Conundrum I have no CompSci background, but I am rather enthusiastic about computers (emphasis on both terms).
With no formal education and zero practical knowledge in the field I know I won&amp;rsquo;t be working around my passion.
I actually tried getting hired by a tech-company but I ended up working for a big IT name, albeit for a less technical role that I had hoped for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I have read so far</title>
      <link>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
