<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>gmnr.github.io</title>
    <link>https://gmnr.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on gmnr.github.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2022 11:01:47 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gmnr.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Breve Storia Della Città di Napoli</title>
      <link>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/storia-napoli/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2022 11:01:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/storia-napoli/</guid>
      <description>I found this book in box that was going to be put away, asked my mom about it and she said it was worth a try.
All in all is not a bad read, but my gripe with it is two faced.
First, the style is not appealing to me at all; phrases often digress to offer the author a chance to use a certain &amp;ldquo;poetic flair&amp;rdquo; that often clouds the understandability of what&amp;rsquo;s being said.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Mind for Numbers</title>
      <link>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/a-mind-for-numbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 16:50:14 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/a-mind-for-numbers/</guid>
      <description>The book is a good read; especially if you are a student.
It can help you adapt and mold your studying strategy in order to maximize your retention and recollection.
The book itself is about having &amp;ldquo;a mind for numbers&amp;rdquo; and improve your stats while learning STEM topics but I think it truly applies to all fields of learning.
What I have not so much liked is that it is heavily oriented towards the education system, helping you &amp;ldquo;passing the tests&amp;rdquo; rather than helping you truly connect with what you&amp;rsquo;re trying to learn and master it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Never Split the Difference - Negotiating As If Your Life Depended On It</title>
      <link>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/never-split-the-difference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 13:22:39 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/never-split-the-difference/</guid>
      <description>The book is a condensed vademecum about negotiation, distilled by none other than Chris Voss, acclaimed author and top FBI-guy negotiator for more than 25 years.
Before reading it, I didn&amp;rsquo;t know if all the buzz about the book was actually due because it is a breathtaking deep dive in the world of negotiations or because Chris&amp;rsquo; company, &amp;ldquo;The Black Swan Group&amp;rdquo; has an amazing marketing department.
Now, I know it is a little bit of both.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Money or Your Life: 9 Steps to Transforming Your Relationship With Money and Achieving Financial Independence</title>
      <link>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/your-money-your-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2021 17:19:37 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/your-money-your-life/</guid>
      <description>I was really excited for this book; so excited that it actually took me more than 4 months to finally finish it (eheh).
I got to this book via a suggestion by Mr. Rip that cites it as a very influential read in the journey towards Financial Independence (FI from now onward).
What is financial Independence? Technically FI is the status of having enough income to pay one&amp;rsquo;s living expenses for the rest of one&amp;rsquo;s life without having to be employed or dependent on others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Happiness Advantage</title>
      <link>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/the-happiness-advantage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 14:10:36 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/the-happiness-advantage/</guid>
      <description>The main concept presented in the book is that the very American (and puritan) equation of:
is substantially flawed.
Instead, corroborated by the recent developments of positive psychology, a better recipe to self-actualization might instead be:
Therefore, the author tries to convey a series of guidelines to help the readers collect happiness boosts during the day in order to pursue their goals.
However, a strong emphasis is put on the results of these methods (rather than their application) which are always presented by the perspective of the author via the numerous talks and presentations he&amp;rsquo;s made on this idea and the feedback that he&amp;rsquo;s received first-hand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aldo Moro - Grandi Delitti nella Storia</title>
      <link>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/grandi-delitti-aldo-moro/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 22:27:12 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/grandi-delitti-aldo-moro/</guid>
      <description>I read this book in one night;
As already mentioned in these reviews, I don&amp;rsquo;t particularly like &amp;ldquo;modern&amp;rdquo; History (and for me modern is everything that happened less than 1.500 years ago); but this beautiful essay by Matteo Albanese showed me that more can be told about events whose sources are contemporary to us (as expected) but in a way that feels genuine and engaging.
Telling a story that has been written rewritten, conspired about, put on other media and much, much discussed is not an easy task, especially from an Historical point of view.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Giuliano de Medici - Grandi Delitti nella Storia</title>
      <link>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/grandi-delitti-giuliano-medici/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 22:18:28 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/grandi-delitti-giuliano-medici/</guid>
      <description>I am not the biggest fan of the Renaissance;
I value its importance in the development of the modern world but my fascination ends there, I am more of a &amp;ldquo;BC&amp;rdquo; kind of guy (or even &amp;ldquo;early AD&amp;rdquo;).
In any case, the murder of Giuliano was sure an important step in defining the future of Firenze.
What the book truly offers is an accurate cross section of what life was in the late Middle Ages with all its cultural fervor and development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cicerone - Grandi Delitti nella Storia</title>
      <link>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/grandi-delitti-cicerone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 May 2021 14:59:59 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/grandi-delitti-cicerone/</guid>
      <description>Following the usual format, the book presents the circumstances surrounding the fall, the flight and the assassination of Rome&amp;rsquo;s most famous orator: Marcus Tullius Cicerone.
In opposition to my likings, it particularly stresses the emotions of Cicerone himself, the indecision, the fear for his family&amp;rsquo;s life, the last moments near is villa in Formia.
Such things, as they really went, are forever lost in History, but in this case that awful dramatization that much I dislike, was not out of place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tiberio - Grandi Delitti nella Storia</title>
      <link>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/grandi-delitti-tiberio/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 23:17:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/grandi-delitti-tiberio/</guid>
      <description>Yet another book from the series of famous murders.
This time I read about the death of the second Emperor of the Romans: Tiberius Caesar Augustus.
This murder wasn&amp;rsquo;t actually an orchestrated political elimination but rather an unexpected necessity.
The story goes that at a rest in Misenum, from a trip from the island of Capri (where the Emperor had his palace) to Rome, Tiberius fell ill and apparently died.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Giulio Cesare - Grandi Delitti nella Storia</title>
      <link>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/grandi-delitti-giulio-cesare/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 22:21:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/grandi-delitti-giulio-cesare/</guid>
      <description>This one was not a surprise, I am a huge fan of Caesar (although I haven&amp;rsquo;t read any monographs yet) and wanting to know more about the circumstances around the famous dictator&amp;rsquo;s death was only natural to me.
The books provides a detailed account about the events that led up and constituted what is the most famous assassination in History (and there&amp;rsquo;s little doubt about that).
The author, using the outline that has characterized this series about famous murders, first presents the backstory of the murder itself answering questions such as:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Filippo II di Macedonia - Grandi Delitti nella Storia</title>
      <link>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/grandi-delitti-filippo-macedone/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 23:36:37 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/grandi-delitti-filippo-macedone/</guid>
      <description>A bit underwhelming.
The authors try and represent a clear picture of the event surrounding the death of Philip II of Macedon, but the accounts and any historical reconstruction is nearly impossible because of the lack of reliable sources.
Therefore, the narrative delves deeper than I would&amp;rsquo;ve liked into dramatization.
I can recommend it as a very light read before going to bed if you&amp;rsquo;re a novice approaching the subject; but otherwise it lacks substance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Kinesis Advantage 2</title>
      <link>https://gmnr.github.io/writing/kinesis-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 22:34:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gmnr.github.io/writing/kinesis-review/</guid>
      <description>What are ergonomic keyboards anyways? The design, usability and concept of an ergonomic keyboard are enhanced features that provide for a more comfortable (or strictly speaking more anatomically correct) typing experience.
In order to do so an ergonomic keyboard might have one of the following (or all):
ortolinear keys: the keys are neatly stacked in line, rather than being aligned diagonally key wells: little depressions that account for the different length of your fingers wrist pads: raised palm rests for a more comfortable typing experience Of course all these &amp;ldquo;improvements&amp;rdquo; come with an hefty premium, that companies charge not only for those upgrades but also for the higher production costs required for an &amp;ldquo;artisanal&amp;rdquo; piece, as these keyboards are hardly mass produced and are almost always mechanic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Gracchi - Grandi Delitti nella Storia</title>
      <link>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/grandi-delitti-i-gracchi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 20:54:02 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/grandi-delitti-i-gracchi/</guid>
      <description>I quite liked this one;
it is the first book I read in 2021 and the first one I came across from the collection of &amp;ldquo;Grandi Delitti della Storia&amp;rdquo; (that translates into: Great Murders of History), a curated series by Corriere della Sera.
I&amp;rsquo;ve always been fascinated by famous murders as they often are breakpoints in the ebb and flow of History and become catalysts of change.
They are also surprisingly often well documented, either because of the morbidity inherent to human nature or maybe because the are a nice break from the apparent plainness of History.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;More&#34;</title>
      <link>https://gmnr.github.io/writing/more/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 18:15:51 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gmnr.github.io/writing/more/</guid>
      <description>A ship in harbor is safe, but that is not what ships are built for On confrontation I am the kind of person that doesn&amp;rsquo;t like confrontation much (both external and internal).
But even so, I recognize the importance of &amp;ldquo;opposition&amp;rdquo;.
I don&amp;rsquo;t mean it literally; I&amp;rsquo;m not suggesting you go challenging everyone and everything in your life but rather that you try and focus inward, always striving to challenge yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My first blog post</title>
      <link>https://gmnr.github.io/writing/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 21:18:45 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gmnr.github.io/writing/first-post/</guid>
      <description>Even a journey of a thousand miles starts with a single step First steps Here it is&amp;hellip; This is my second blog post, ever.
Why not the first? Because this is the second time that I try blogging.
I&amp;rsquo;m quite excited to start this journey (again), but I&amp;rsquo;m left with some doubts; one above all: will I be able to keep the commitment and write every now and then?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://gmnr.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gmnr.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi, my name is Guido.
I play music (with varied degrees of success and instruments) and I like computers.
The Computer Conundrum I have no CompSci background, but I am rather enthusiastic about computers (emphasis on both terms).
With no formal education and zero practical knowledge in the field I know I won&amp;rsquo;t be working around my passion.
I actually tried getting hired by a tech-company but I ended up working for a big IT name, albeit for a less technical role that I had hoped for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I have read so far</title>
      <link>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gmnr.github.io/reading/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
